# CURRICULUM VITAE

Vincent MacKay, PhD Candidate, University of Toronto Citizenship: Canadian

vincent.mackay@mail.utoronto.ca | vincentmackay.github.io

# Research interests

I develop **instrumentation** for long wavelength radio observatories, specializing in mutual coupling mitigation in close-packed array. I devise **data analysis** methods for removing foregrounds from cosmological data. The scientific goals that motivate my work are **21 cm intensity mapping**, and detection of **fast radio bursts** (**FRBs**).

# **Education**

CAD \$2,000.00

PhD, Physics (expected graduation: summer 2023)	2019-present
University of Toronto, Toronto	
Supervisor: Professor Keith Vanderlinde	
MSc, Physics (one year, fast-tracked)	2018-2019
University of Toronto, Toronto	
Supervisor: Professor Keith Vanderlinde	
BSc, First-Class Honours, Mathematics and Physics	2015-2018
McGill University, Montréal	
BMus, Piano performance	2012-2018
Conservatoire de musique de Québec, Québec City	
Research experience	
Graduate research in Physics	2018-present
Designing, manufacturing, and testing ultra wideband feeds and receiving systems	
Simulating dishes and arrays to model and mitigate mutual coupling	
Leading the team in charge of deploying the analog instrumentation for CHORD prototypes	
Analyzing large radio interferometric data products from the CHIME telescope	
University of Toronto, Toronto	
Undergraduate research in Physics and Physiology	2017–2019
Modeling re-entry in cardiac tissue and other nonlinear patterns in excitable media McGill University, Montréal	
Undergraduate research in Physics	Summer 2017
Simulating high energy $pp$ collisions to compare graviton models against data from the LHC University of Alberta, Edmonton	
Undergraduate research in Physics	Summer 2016
Developing a low-cost Compton imaging device for locating sources of gamma rays	
McGill University, Montréal	
Competitive scholarships and awards	
Ontario Graduate Scholarship	2020-2021
CAD \$15,000.00	
University of Alberta Undergraduate Summer Research Award	Summer 2017
CAD \$8,000.00	
NSERC Undergraduate Summer Research Award	$Summer\ 2016$
CAD \$4,500.00	
FRQNT Supplement to NSERC	$Summer\ 2016$

# **Publications**

# As (co-)lead author

- 1. Vincent MacKay, Mark Lai, et al. Low-cost, Low-loss, Ultra-wideband Miniaturized Feed for Modern Interferometric Radio Telescopes. Submitted to the *Journal of Astronomical Instrumentation*, 2022 arXiv:2210.07477 PhD work
- 2. Eric N. Cytrynbaum, Vincent MacKay, et al. Double-wave reentry in excitable media. *Chaos: An Interdisci*plinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, 29(7):073103, 2019

Undergraduate work

# As contributing author

- 3. Devin Crichton, Moumita Aich, et al. Hydrogen Intensity and Real-Time Analysis Experiment: 256-element array status and overview. *Journal of Astronomical Telescopes, Instruments, and Systems*, 8(1):011019, 2022 PhD work
- 4. Benjamin R. B. Saliwanchik, Aaron Ewall-Wice, et al. Mechanical and optical design of the HIRAX radio telescope. In Heather K. Marshall, Jason Spyromilio, et al., editors, *Ground-based and Airborne Telescopes VIII*, volume 11445, page 114455O. International Society for Optics and Photonics, SPIE, 2021

PhD work

## **Talks**

#### Conference talks

1. National Radio Science Meeting

Boulder, CO, USA, 2023

"An Ultra-Wideband, Low-Loss, Low-Cost Feed Design for Large-N, Small-D Observatories, and Implementation on CHORD"

2. URSI Atlantic Radio Science Meeting

Gran Canaria, Spain, 2022

"Hardware Design and Array Layout for CHORD: the Canadian Hydrogen Observatory and Radio-transient Detector"

3. National Radio Science Meeting

Boulder, CO, USA (online), 2022

"Design Considerations for CHORD: the Canadian Hydrogen Observatory and Radio-transient Detector"

4. Science at Low Frequencies Conference

Fully online conference, 2020

"The Canadian Hydrogen Observatory and Radio-transient Detector (CHORD): Feed and Dish Design and Trade-offs"

5. IEEE AP-S/URSI Conference

Montréal, Canada (online), 2020

"A Miniaturized Ultra-Wideband, Low-Loss, Low-Cost Feed for Astrophysics"

6. Society for Mathematical Biology Annual Meeting

Montréal, Canada, 2019

"Double-wave Reentry in Excitable Media"

#### Colloquium and seminar talks

6. Astronomy and Space Physics Seminar, Kansas University

Lawrence, KS, USA (online), 2021

"Cosmology and Detection of Radio Transients with CHORD: Science Goals and Design Considerations"

7. Summer colloquium, Department of Physics, University of Toronto

Toronto, Canada (online), 2020

"Development of CHORD: the Canadian Hydrogen Observatory and Radio-transient Detector"

#### Outreach talks

8. Astronomy on Tap NYC: Cosmic Happy Hour

New York, NY, USA (online), 2022

"The Hubble Tension: A Crisis of Cosmic Proportions"

9. Cosmos From Your Couch

Toronto, Canada (online), 2020

"Peeking into the Invisible Universe with Radio Astronomy"

# **Teaching**

Teaching Assistant, University of Toronto

PHY293: Waves and Modern Physics Fall 2020, Fall 2022

Grading exams

PHY250: Electricity and Magnetism

Summer 2022

Preparing and leading tutorials

PHY294: Quantum and Thermal Physics Winter 2022

Preparing and leading tutorials, grading exams

PHY151: Foundations of Physics I Fall 2018, Fall 2021

Leading practical activities, grading assignments and exams

PHY205: The Physics of Everyday Life Summer 2021

Preparing and leading tutorials, grading assignments and projects

PHY491/1491: Current Interpretations of Quantum Mechanics Winter 2021

Grading assignments

PHY207: The Physics of Music Winter 2020, Winter 2021

Preparing and leading tutorials, grading assignments and projects

PHY100: The Magic of Physics Fall 2019

Preparing and leading tutorials, grading assignments and projects, and finals

PHY132: Introduction to Physics II Winter 2019

Leading practical activities, grading assignments and exams

# Community involvement

## Advisor for the Physics Directed Reading Program

Elaborating a reading list and schedule on advanced topics in physics for two undergraduate students (topic chosen: observational cosmology)

Meeting with the students at least ten times during the 2022-23 school year to discuss the readings and solidify their understanding

Guiding the students through small coding projects, and setting up a poster presentation

## Member of the organizing committee for the 2021 Dunlap Instrumentation Lectures

Helping organize a week-long virtual lecture series with invited speakers and visiting student researchers Organizing and leading a coding and data analysis workshop for visiting scholars, called *Radio signal detection and the properties of thermal radiation and noise* 

#### Judge at young scientist competitions

2021 Canada-Wide Science Fair (CWSF)

2021 Canadian Undergraduate Physics Conference (CUPC)

## President of the Physics Graduate Student Association 2019-2020

Organizing social activities for physics graduate students, representing them at the graduate student union

#### Other volunteering activities

Leading lab tours for University of Toronto's AstroTours

Representing the Dunlap Institute at the 2022 Black Excellence in STEM and Medicine (BE-STEMM) conference career fair

Discussing with grade school students on video calls as part of the Skype a Scientist program